Guide to the Anna Wipfler Senior Essay and Interviews Documenting Lesbian and Gay Student Activism at Yale
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Anna Wipfler senior essay and interviews documenting lesbian and gay student activism at Yale
2008-2009
RU 1097
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
38 boxes
1904.64
The papers consist of Anna Wipfler's (Yale 2009) senior essay, "The Making of 'the Gay Ivy': A History of Lesbian and Gay Student Organizing at Yale, 1969-1987" and her interviews with lesbian and gay Yale alumni.
Wipfler, Anna
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 49 (YRG 49), Papers and projects on Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Anna Wipfler, 2009.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the papers is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
Anna Wipfler graduated with a B.A. from Yale College in 2009. Her senior essay research focused on gay and lesbian student activism at Yale College in the 1970s and 1980s.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of Anna Wipfler's senior essay, "The Making of 'the Gay Ivy': A History of Lesbian and Gay Student Organizing at Yale, 1969-1987" and her oral history interviews with lesbian and gay Yale alumni. The papers document gay and lesbian student life and activism at Yale and in New Haven, Connecticut. Student organizations including the Gay Alliance at Yale, the YaLesbians, the Gay and Lesbian Coop, and the Yale Women's Center are well documented in the interviews.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by format; interviews are arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewee.
Bisexuality; College students; Gay liberation movement; Gay men -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Homosexuality; Lesbianism; Lesbians -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Students -- Political activity; Transsexualism; LGBTQ resource; Wipfler, Anna; Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender Cooperative at Yale; Yale University -- Students
- Anna Wipfler senior essay and interviews, 2008-2009; Accession 2010-A-018
  - Wipfler, Anna, "The Making of 'the Gay Ivy': A History of Lesbian and Gay Student Organizing at Yale, 1969-1987", 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The materials are open for research.
  - Interviews
    - Albert, Fred, 2008 August 9; Computer file (QuickTime)
      Biographical / Historical
      Albert graduated from Yale College in 1979.
      Closed to research until January 1, 2060.
    - Ayres, Tara, 2008 August 18; Computer file (QuickTime)
      Scope and Contents
      Ayres grew up in Kansas City and graduated from Yale College in 1981. She lived in New Haven from 1975 to 1981. She lived off-campus and considered herself a member of the New Haven lesbian community. Topics covered in the interview include the Gay Alliance at Yale, co-founding of YaLesbians, the Yale Women's Center, the New Haven lesbian community, the New Haven Women's Liberation Center, and student and community interactions. Also discussed are the issues that were relevant to Ayres and her cohort including feminism, radical lesbian feminism, racism, classism, and social justice and peace work.
      - Use copy, Compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 2U)
    - Baird, Steve, 2008 July 22; Computer file (QuickTime)
      Baird graduated from Yale College in 1982.
      - Use copy (part 1), compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 3Ua)
      - Use copy (part 2), compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 3Ub)
    - Borten, Larry, 2009 February 7; Computer file (QuickTime)
      Borten graduated from Yale College in 1982,
      - Use copy, Compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 4U)
    - Chadwick, Peter, 2008 August 19; Computer file (QuickTime)
      Chadwick graduated from Yale College in 1985.
      - Use copy, Compact disc (Audio CD) (Box 5U)